Indiana University Writers' Conference records, 1940-2009 C444
Indiana University Archives
Indiana University Writers' Conference records
1940-2009
Indiana University Archives
Indiana University Writers' Conference
C444
6.1 cubic feet 8 boxes; 1 oversize folder
Held annually since 1940, the Indiana University Writers' Conference provides workshops and classes that offer writers of all levels the opportunity to learn from a faculty of well-known and award-winning authors. Correspondence between Conference staff and potential faculty members as well as various administrative files are represented in the contents of this collection.
Access Restrictions
Due to prevalence of personally identifiable information such as Social Security numbers throughout the collection, advance notice is required for access so that staff may redact sensitive information before making it available for research.
Administrative History
Begun in 1940 and held annually each year except for two years during World War II, the Indiana University Writers' Conference was originally organized by IU English professor Cecelia H. Hendricks to provide aspiring writers with the opportunity to learn from and interact with more experienced and often nationally renowned or award-winning authors.
Throughout its history, Conference Directors such as Ralph Collins, who took over in 1941, Robert Mitchner, and Roger Mitchell, amongst many others, and up until the current Director, Bob Bledsoe, have reached out over the years to numerous authors, editors, and literary agents to lead workshops in fiction, nonfiction, and poetry. Other topics, such as radio scripts and blogging reflected the writing styles and techniques popular to their day.
Though much of the correspondence within this collection represents failed efforts to convince well-known authors to present at the Conference, many of staff's efforts were successful, bringing a variety of significant literary figures to teach in Bloomington. As noted by Kurt Vonnegut, a 1964 faculty member, it's "the most respectable writers' conference I know."
Arrangement
Collection is organized into two series, Writers' files and Administrative files.
Scope and Content Note
This collection is comprised of records from 1940 to 2009 that represent the planning and administration of the annual Indiana University Writers' Conference.
The Writers' files series consists of correspondence between Conference staff and potential faculty spanning 1940-2004. The series is arranged alphabetically by surname. Many of the files hold regrets of the author but for those who did agree to serve conference faculty, the files hold correspondence detailing their plans. Notable authors with which staff corresponded include Margaret Atwood, Ray Bradbury, John Steinbeck, and IU alum Don Herold.
The Administrative files series, 1940-2009, is comprised of promotional items such as newsletters, press releases, posters, and brochures, as well as schedules of events, various correspondence, and lists of faculty members. Notable within this series is a detailed and thorough history of the Conference within the file titled "Writers' Conference History, 1993."
Related Material
Additional records such as newsletters, annual reports, bulletins, and publications may be accessed in the Archives of Institutional Memory.
Archived web sites for the Conference may be included in Archive-It.
Acquisition Information
Accession 2007/012
Provenance
Transferred to the Archives by the Writers' Conference in February 2007; Accession 2007/012.
Appraisal
Duplicate documents, financial documents and receipts, as well as participant lists, evaluations, and transcripts were weeded from the collection.
Writers' workshops --Indiana --Bloomington.; Writers' retreats --Indiana --Bloomington.; Authors, American --Indiana --Congresses.; Indiana University Writers' Conference -- Records and correspondence; Indiana University Writers' Conference -- History -- Sources
- Writers' files, 1940-2004; undated (Box 1)
  - Abbey, Edward, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
  - Adams, Leone, 1955-1956 (Box 1)
  - Abádi-Nagy, Zoltán, 1988-1989 (Box 1)
  - Aiken, Conrad, 1940-1944 (Box 1)
  - Ainsworth, Norma, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - Aleshire, Joan, 1988-1989 (Box 1)
  - Alessio, Carolyn, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Lloyd, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
  - Aley, Maxwell, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Algren, Nelson, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Allen, Dick, 1967-1975 (Box 1)
  - Allen, John, 1969-1974 (Box 1)
  - Alpert, Barry, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Robert, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Angel, Ralph, undated (Box 1)
  - Anshaw, Carol, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Apple, Max, 1980-1984 (Box 1)
  - Appleman, Marjorie, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Arden, John, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Ardizzone, Tony, undated (Box 1)
  - Ardrey, Robert, 1947 (Box 1)
  - Arthur, Elizabeth, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Ashbery, John, 1965-1969 (Box 1)
  - Ashton, Brad, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Atcheson, Richard, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Atkinson, Brooks, 1942 (Box 1)
  - Atwood, Margaret, 1978-1985 (Box 1)
  - Auden, W.H., 1946-1950 (Box 1)
  - Axelrod, Steven, 1986 (Box 1)
  - A – Misc. Letters, 1940-1948 (Box 1)
  - Bacon, Peggy, 1957-1958 (Box 1)
  - Baen, James, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Baker, Elliott, 1961-1969 (Box 1)
  - Baldwin, Hanson, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Bambara, Toni Cade, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Baral, Robert, 1963-1966 (Box 1)
  - Barnouw, Erik, 1946-1956 (Box 1)
  - Barnstone, Willis, 1966-1982 (Box 1)
  - Barthelme, Frederick, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Basso, Hamilton, 1940-1961 (Box 1)
  - Batchelor, John Calvin, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Baxter, Charles, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Beattie, Anne, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Beatty, Jerome, 1959-1966 (Box 1)
  - Bell, Marvin, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
  - Bellow, Saul, 1958-1976 (Box 1)
  - Benchley, Nathaniel, 1957-1964 (Box 1)
  - Bendall, Molly, undated (Box 1)
  - Benedict, Pinckney, undated (Box 1)
  - Benet, Marjorie Flack, 1950-1951 (Box 1)
  - Benet, Stephen Vincent, 1940-1942 (Box 1)
  - Benson, Sally, 1941 (Box 1)
  - Berge, Carol, 1977-1984 (Box 1)
  - Berry, Wendell, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
  - Bertolino, Jim, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Betts, Doris, 1972-1984 (Box 1)
  - Birmingham, Stephen, 1969-1974 (Box 1)
  - Blackmur, R.P., 1947-1950 (Box 1)
  - Blakemore, Barbara, 1959-1975 (Box 1)
  - Bliven, Bruce and Naomi, 1954-1966 (Box 1)
  - Blume, Judy, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Blumenthal, Gertrude, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Bly, Carol, 1983-1985 (Box 1)
  - Bly, Robert, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Bogan, Louise, 1949-1955 (Box 1)
  - Boles, Paul Darcy, 1969-1975 (Box 1)
  - Booth, Philip, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Boruch, Marianne, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Boswell, Robert, 1991-1993 (Box 1)
  - Bovasso, Julie, undated (Box 1)
  - Bowen, Elizabeth, 1951 (Box 1)
  - Bowman, Cathy, 1996-1998 (Box 1)
  - Bracken, Tom, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Bradbury, Ray, 1958-1961 (Box 1)
  - Bradley, David, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Brady, John, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Brand, Millen, 1948-1949 (Box 1)
  - Brickell, Herschel, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Brinnin, John Malcolm, 1953 (Box 1)
  - Bromfield, Louis, 1942-1956 (Box 1)
  - Broner, E.M., 1981-1984 (Box 1)
  - Brooks, Gwendolyn, 1965-1985 (Box 1)
  - Brooks, John, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Brown, James Oliver, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
  - Brown, John Mason, 1940-1942 (Box 1)
  - Bruchac, III, Joseph, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Bryan, Sharon, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Burack, A.S., 1973 (Box 1)
  - Burgin, Richard, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Burnett, Whit, 1948-1963 (Box 1)
  - Burns, John Horne, 1948-1974 (Box 1)
  - Burns, Ralph, 1989-1998 (Box 1)
  - B – Misc. Letters, 1941-1971 (Box 1)
  - Cady, Howard, 1968-1975 (Box 1)
  - Cage, John, 1977-1979 (Box 1)
  - Cahill, Tim, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
  - Calisher, Hortense, 1958-1964 (Box 1)
  - Callaway, Nancy, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Campbell, W.S., 1950 (Box 1)
  - Canzoneri, Robert, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
  - Carmer, Carl, 1941-1962 (Box 1)
  - Carr, Pat, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Carruth, Hayden, 1979-1984 (Box 1)
  - Carver, Raymond, 1981-1984 (Box 1)
  - R.V. Cassill, 1981-1985 (Box 1)
  - Cather, Willa, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Cavanah, Frances, 1947-1960 (Box 1)
  - Cecil, Richard, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Chaikin, Miriam, 1969-1973 (Box 1)
  - Chase, Ilka, 1967-1968 (Box 1)
  - Chase, Joan, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Cheever, John, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Cherry, Kelly, 1983-1986 (Box 1)
  - Chute, B.J. (Joy), 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - Ciardi, John, 1951-1956 (Box 1)
  - Clifford, James, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Clinton, D. (Dewitt), 1981 (Box 1)
  - Cohn, David, 1947 (Box 1)
  - Colby, Jean Poindexter, 1956-1968 (Box 1)
  - Congdon, Don, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Connell, Evan, 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - Conroy, Pat, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Corwin, Norman, 1945-1950 (Box 1)
  - Costanzo, Gerald, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Coughlan, Robert, 1953-1954 (Box 1)
  - Cousin, Michelle, 1957-1959 (Box 1)
  - Cousins, Norman, 1946 (Box 1)
  - Cox, R. David, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
  - Cozzens, James Gould, 1941-1949 (Box 1)
  - Creighton, Beatrice, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Crichton, Robert, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Cromie, Robert (Box 1)
  - Cryer, Gretchen, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
  - Cummings, E.E., 1951 (Box 2)
  - Cummings, Parke, 1962-1963 (Box 2)
  - C – Misc. Letters, 1941-1965 (Box 2)
  - Daiches, David, 1942-1947 (Box 2)
  - Daniels, Mary, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Danish, Barbara, undated (Box 2)
  - Dark, Harris Edward, 1974-1976 (Box 2)
  - Davidson, Donald, 1942-1944 (Box 2)
  - Day, Robert, 1980-1981 (Box 2)
  - Delmonte, Helen, 1985 (Box 2)
  - De Regniers, Beatrice Schenk, 1961-1967 (Box 2)
  - Detzer, Karl, 1941-1949 (Box 2)
  - Dew, Robb Forman, undated (Box 2)
  - Didion, Joan, 1977-1980 (Box 2)
  - Digges, Deborah, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Dillard, Annie, 1984-1985 (Box 2)
  - Distelheim, Rochelle, 1985-1988 (Box 2)
  - Doctorow, E.L., 1976-1977 (Box 2)
  - Dodd, Susan, 1990-1991 (Box 2)
  - Dodd, Wayne, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Donaldson, Ross, 1955 (Box 2)
  - Dos Passos, John, 1946-1956 (Box 2)
  - Dostal, Cy, 1976-1977 (Box 2)
  - Dubie, Norman, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Dubus, Andre, 1983-1986 (Box 2)
  - Dugan, Alan, 1979-1990 (Box 2)
  - Dunlop, Richard, 1970-1974 (Box 2)
  - D – Misc. Letters, 1941-1964 (Box 2)
  - Eberhart, Richard, 1951 (Box 2)
  - Eisenstein, Phyllis, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Elkin, Stanley, 1972-1983 (Box 2)
  - Elledge, Jim, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Elliott, 1962-1965 (Box 2)
  - Ellison, Ralph, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Eimers, Nancy, undated (Box 2)
  - Elmo, Ann, 1963-1975 (Box 2)
  - Emmanuel, Lynn, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Englund, Ken, undated (Box 2)
  - Enright, Elizabeth, 1952-1967 (Box 2)
  - Enslin, Theodore, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Ephron, Nora, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Ethridge, Willie Snow, 1962 (Box 2)
  - Eustis, Helen, 1956 (Box 2)
  - E – Misc. Letters, 1951-1965 (Box 2)
  - Falck, Colin, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Farrell, James T., 1945 (Box 2)
  - Fast, Howard, 1947 (Box 2)
  - Faulkner, William, 1946-1949 (Box 2)
  - Fearing, Kenneth, 1947-1948 (Box 2)
  - Finneran, William J., 1963-1972 (Box 2)
  - Finney, Gertrude, 1965-1967 (Box 2)
  - Flanner, Janet, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Fletcher, John Gould, 1940-1942 (Box 2)
  - Ford, Jesse Hill, 1968-1973 (Box 2)
  - Fornes, Maria Irena, 1978 (Box 2)
  - Foster, Malcolm, 1962-1967 (Box 2)
  - Franco, Marjorie, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Frank, Gerold, 1967-1972 (Box 2)
  - Frederick, John T., 1941-1942 (Box 2)
  - Freeman, Jean Todd, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - Freeman, Judith, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Friarmood, Elisabeth Hamilton, 1959-1962 (Box 2)
  - Fuller, Muriel, 1950-1951 (Box 2)
  - Furlong, William Barry, 1971 (Box 2)
  - F – Misc. Letters, 1940-1965 (Box 2)
  - Gallagher, Tess, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Garrett, George, 1979-1982 (Box 2)
  - Garrigue, Jean, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Gass, William, 1969-1982 (Box 2)
  - Gassner, John, 1947-1948 (Box 2)
  - Gegenheimer, Albert, 1983-1984 (Box 2)
  - Gehman, Richard, 1960-1963 (Box 2)
  - Georgakas, Dan, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Gerson, Noel B., 1970-1975 (Box 2)
  - Gerstler, Amy, 1997-1998 (Box 2)
  - Gethers, Peter, 1979-1981 (Box 2)
  - Gibbons, Reginald, 1989-1995 (Box 2)
  - Gibson, Walker, 1957-1967 (Box 2)
  - Glave, Thomas, 2003-2004 (Box 2)
  - Glück, Louise, 1983-1985 (Box 2)
  - Godine, David, 1976-1984 (Box 2)
  - Godwin, Gail, 1980-1983 (Box 2)
  - Goedicke, Patricia, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Gold, Herbert, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Goldstein, Laurence, 1986-1987 (Box 2)
  - Gonzalez, Jr., Arturo F., 1967-1973 (Box 2)
  - Goodman Associates, 1983-1984 (Box 2)
  - Gordon, Caroline, 1950-1955 (Box 2)
  - Gray, Francine, 1977-1983 (Box 2)
  - Graham, Philip, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Green, Paul, 1941-1946 (Box 2)
  - Greenberg, Al, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Greene, Jonathan, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Gregor, Arthur, 1972-1975 (Box 2)
  - Gregory, Horace, 1944-1947 (Box 2)
  - Grice, Julia, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Griffiths, Trevor, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Gross, Martin, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Gubar, Ed, 1978 (Box 2)
  - Guthrie, A.B., 1948-1952 (Box 2)
  - G – Misc. Letters, 1949-1970 (Box 2)
  - Hailey, Arthur, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Hall, Donald, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Halliday, Mark, undated (Box 2)
  - Hamburger, Philip, 1969-1975 (Box 2)
  - Hampl, Patricia, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Harris, Janet I., 1980 (Box 2)
  - Harris, Mark, 1960-1985 (Box 2)
  - Harrison, Barbara G., 1983-1985 (Box 2)
  - Hartke, Vance, 1963 (Box 2)
  - Hartman, Jan, 1967-1968 (Box 2)
  - Hass, Robert, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Havemann, Ernest, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Havighurst, Walter, 1941-1946 (Box 2)
  - Hawkes, John, 1982-1984 (Box 2)
  - Haydn, Hiram, 1948-1957 (Box 2)
  - Hayes, Joseph, 1966-1972 (Box 2)
  - Hayes, Terrance, 2003-2004 (Box 2)
  - Hazard, James, 1974-1984 (Box 2)
  - Head, Gwen, 1983-1984 (Box 2)
  - Heaney, Seamus, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Hellman, Lillian, 1946-1948 (Box 2)
  - Helprin, Mark, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Henderson, Robert, 1954-1957 (Box 2)
  - Henley, Patricia, 1979; 2003-2004 (Box 2)
  - Henry, DeWitt, 1988-1989 (Box 2)
  - Herold, Don, 1946 (Box 2)
  - Hersey, John, 1948-1977 (Box 2)
  - Heyliger, William, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Higdon, Hal, 1965-1974 (Box 2)
  - Hillman, Brenda, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Hillyer, Robert, 1945-1948 (Box 2)
  - Hirsch, Edward, undated (Box 2)
  - Hoagland, Tony, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Hochman, Sandra, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Hodapp, William, 1955 (Box 2)
  - Hoff, Syd, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Hofstadter, Doug, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Hongo, Garrett, 1987-1988 (Box 2)
  - Hotchner, A.E., 1972-1973 (Box 2)
  - Hougan, Jim, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Howe, W.E., 1940 (Box 2)
  - Hudgins, Andrew, 1988-1989 (Box 2)
  - Hughes, Merritt, 1941 (Box 2)
  - Hughes, Ted, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Hugo, Richard, 1976-1982 (Box 3)
  - Hull, Lynda, 1989-1990 (Box 3)
  - Humphries, Rolfe, 1947-1956 (Box 3)
  - Hunnicutt, Ellen, 1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - Hunt, Mabel Leigh, 1948 (Box 3)
  - Hunt, Morton, 1969 (Box 3)
  - H – Misc. Letters, 1941-1971 (Box 3)
  - Ignatow, David, 1978 (Box 3)
  - Inge, William, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Ives, Vernon, 1959 (Box 3)
  - Jackson, James, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Jackson, Margaret Weymouth, 1941-1966 (Box 3)
  - Jackson, Richard, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Jacobsen, Josephine, undated (Box 3)
  - Janeway, Elizabeth, 1961-1966 (Box 3)
  - Jarman, Mark, undated (Box 3)
  - Jarrell, Randall, undated (Box 3)
  - Jarrett, Beverly, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Jauss, Dave, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Jennings, John, 1966 (Box 3)
  - Jensen, Eileen, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Jensen, Laura, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Jensen, Oliver, 1952-1962 (Box 3)
  - Johnson, Josephine, 1946-1965 (Box 3)
  - Jones, Preston, undated (Box 3)
  - Jones, Richard, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Jones, Rodney, 1998 (Box 3)
  - Joseph Allison, 1998 (Box 3)
  - Joseph, Nannine, 1941 (Box 3)
  - Judson, Clara Ingram, 1960-1966 (Box 3)
  - Justice, Donald, 1982-1985 (Box 3)
  - Kantor, MacKinley, 1941-1966 (Box 3)
  - Katrovas, Richard, 1996-1997 (Box 3)
  - Kaufman, Bel, 1967-1969 (Box 3)
  - Kaufman, Shirley, 1981-1982 (Box 3)
  - Kelly, Brigit Pegeen, 1992-2004 (Box 3)
  - Kemelman, Harry, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Kercheval, Jesse Lee, 1998-1999 (Box 3)
  - Kimball, Philip, undated (Box 3)
  - Kincaid, Jamaica, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Kingston, Maxine Hong, 1978 (Box 3)
  - Kinnell, Galway, 1979-1985 (Box 3)
  - Kinoy, Ernest, 1959-1960 (Box 3)
  - Kizer, Carolyn, 1980-1985 (Box 3)
  - Knoepfle, John, undated (Box 3)
  - Koch, Kenneth, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Koenig, Rhoda, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Komunyakaa, Yusef, 1986-1987 (Box 3)
  - Kosinski, Jerzy, 1977-1981 (Box 3)
  - Kostelanetz, Richard, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Kramer, Sydelle, 1978 (Box 3)
  - Krauss, Ruth, 1956-1963 (Box 3)
  - Kroll, Harry Harrison, 1941 (Box 3)
  - Kumin, Maxine, 1981-1985 (Box 3)
  - K – Misc. Letters, 1941-1965 (Box 3)
  - La Cossitt, Henry, 1955-1959 (Box 3)
  - Larsen, Anne, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Lathem, Jean Lee, 1959-1973 (Box 3)
  - Lawrence, Jerome, 1946-1948 (Box 3)
  - Leach, Peter, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Lee, Li-Young, 2004 (Box 3)
  - LeGuin, Ursula, 1975-1985 (Box 3)
  - Leithauser, Brad, 1998 (Box 3)
  - L'Engle, Madeleine, 1965-1975 (Box 3)
  - Lenski, Lois, 1956-1963 (Box 3)
  - Lescher, Robert, 1963-1966 (Box 3)
  - Lesser, Ellen, 1988-1990 (Box 3)
  - Lessing, Doris, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Le Sueur, Meridel, 1947 (Box 3)
  - Levertov, Denise, 1979-1985 (Box 3)
  - Levine, Philip, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Lewis, Naome, 1969 (Box 3)
  - Liebling, A.J., 1949-1950 (Box 3)
  - Lilly, Eli, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Lincoln, Victoria, 1952 (Box 3)
  - Long, Laura, 1950 (Box 3)
  - Lopez, Barry, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Lowell, Robert, 1948-1952 (Box 3)
  - Lowenstein, Barbara, 1978 (Box 3)
  - Luce, Clare Boothe, 1941 (Box 3)
  - Lurie, Alison, 1982 (Box 3)
  - Lux, Thomas, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Lytle, Andrew, 1949 (Box 3)
  - L – Misc. Letters, 1940-1967 (Box 3)
  - MacDonald, John, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Mailer, Norman, 1951-1952 (Box 3)
  - Maltz, Albert, 1945-1947 (Box 3)
  - Mamet, David, 1977-1978 (Box 3)
  - Marchetti, Victor, undated (Box 3)
  - Marquand, John, 1947-1951 (Box 3)
  - Marshall, Paule, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Martin, George R.R., 1976 (Box 3)
  - Martin, Madelyn Pugh, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Martin, John Bartlow, 1950-1959 (Box 3)
  - Martinez, Manuel Luis, 1998 (Box 3)
  - Martone, Michael, 2003-2004 (Box 3)
  - Mason, Bobbie Ann, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Mason, Miriam E., 1962-1966 (Box 3)
  - Masterson, Peter, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Mathis, Cleopatra, 1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - Matthews, Jack, 1964-1975 (Box 3)
  - Matthews, William, 1991 (Box 3)
  - Matthiessen, Peter, 1981-1982 (Box 3)
  - Maxwell, William, 1946-1957 (Box 3)
  - McCluskey, John, 1980-1998 (Box 3)
  - McCullers, Carson, 1956 (Box 3)
  - McElderry, Margaret, 1956-1959 (Box 3)
  - McGuane, Margaret, 1981-1982 (Box 3)
  - McHugh, Heather, 1991 (Box 3)
  - McKnight, Reginald, 1989-1991 (Box 3)
  - McMeekin, Isabel, 1951-1952 (Box 3)
  - McPhee, John, 1980-1985 (Box 3)
  - McPherson, Sandra, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Medina, Kate, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Meek, Jay, 1997-1998 (Box 3)
  - Meredith, Robert, 1965-1967 (Box 3)
  - Mernit, Susan, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Merwin, W.S., 1980-1981 (Box 3)
  - Metcalf, Paul, 1974-1975 (Box 3)
  - Michaels, Leonard, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Milesko-Pytel, Diana, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Miller, Alyce, 2003-2004 (Box 3)
  - Miller, Arthur, 1947-1952 (Box 3)
  - Miller, M. Hughes, 1959-1967 (Box 3)
  - Miller, Merle, 1950-1951 (Box 3)
  - Mitchell, Roger, 1975-1981 (Box 3)
  - Montag, Tom, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Montgomery, Ruth, 1965-1966 (Box 3)
  - Moore, Brian, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Morrison, Toni, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Mortone, Michael, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Mosel, Tad, 1962-1976 (Box 3)
  - Mowat, Farley, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Mueller, Lisel, 1980-1985 (Box 3)
  - Munson, Gorham, 1948-1969 (Box 3)
  - Murphy, George, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Murphy, Robert, 1962-1964 (Box 3)
  - Myrer, Anton, 1968-1972 (Box 3)
  - M – Misc. Letters, 1941-1963 (Box 3)
  - Naslund, Sena Jeter, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Nathan, Robert, undated (Box 3)
  - Naylor, Gloria, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Nelson, Antonia, 1992 (Box 4)
  - Nemerov, Howard, 1956 (Box 4)
  - Neugeboren, Jay, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Neville, Emily Cheney, 1971-1982 (Box 4)
  - Neville, Susan, 1985-1995 (Box 4)
  - Newquist, Roy, 1964-1967 (Box 4)
  - Nims, John Frederick, 1948-1949 (Box 4)
  - Nixon, Cornelia, 1988-1996 (Box 4)
  - Noble, Don, 1982-1983 (Box 4)
  - Nolan, Jeannette Covert, 1959-1965 (Box 4)
  - Nolan, Val, 1941-1949 (Box 4)
  - Nordloh, David, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Nordstrom, Ursula, 1956-1963 (Box 4)
  - Norman, Gurney, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Norman, Howard, 1986-1987 (Box 4)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Oboler, Arch, 1948-1949 (Box 4)
  - O'Connor, Edwin, 1957-1958 (Box 4)
  - O'Hara, John, 1947 (Box 4)
  - Oliver, Mary, 1983-1984 (Box 4)
  - Olsen, Jack, 1963-1969 (Box 4)
  - Olsen, William, undated (Box 4)
  - Ondaatje, Michael, 1983-1984 (Box 4)
  - O'Rourke, William, 1997-1998 (Box 4)
  - O – Misc. Letters, 1947-1959 (Box 4)
  - Padgett, Ron, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Paley, Grace, 1976-1986 (Box 4)
  - Papenhausen, Carol, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Parisi, Joseph, Poetry Magazine, 1983-1988 (Box 4)
  - Parker, James Reid, 1963-1964 (Box 4)
  - Pastan, Linda, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Paterson, Katherine, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Patton, Frances Gray, 1953-1960 (Box 4)
  - Peden, William, 1965-1970 (Box 4)
  - Percy, Walker, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Perillo, Lucia, 1997-1998 (Box 4)
  - Perry, Bernard, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Peters, Bob, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Peterson, Len, 1948 (Box 4)
  - Petrakis, Harry Mark, 1964-1975 (Box 4)
  - Phillips, Jayne Anne, 1982-1984 (Box 4)
  - Pickrel, Paul, 1954 (Box 4)
  - Piercy, Marge, 1977-1986 (Box 4)
  - Plumly, Stanley, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Polking, Kirk, 1964-1974 (Box 4)
  - Polsgrove, Carol, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Poole, William, 1958-1967 (Box 4)
  - Porter, Katherine Anne, 1942-1953 (Box 4)
  - Powell, Dawn, 1963 (Box 4)
  - Powell, Jim, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Powers, J.F., 1952-1954 (Box 4)
  - Prokosch, Frederic, 1941-1946 (Box 4)
  - Quinn, Kerker, 1941 (Box 4)
  - Rabbitt, Tom, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Rabe, David, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Ramsey, Paul, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Ramsey, William, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Ransom, John Crowe, 1940-1950 (Box 4)
  - Rawlings, Marjorie Kinna, 1942-1946 (Box 4)
  - Reed, Ishmael, 1978-1981 (Box 4)
  - Remsberg, Charles and Bonnie, 1972 (Box 4)
  - Revell, Donald, 1991 (Box 4)
  - Reynolds, Paul, 1967-1968 (Box 4)
  - Rexroth, Kenneth, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Rice, Elmer, 1946-1947 (Box 4)
  - Rich, Adrienne, 1958-1985 (Box 4)
  - Riggs, Lynn, 1940-1947 (Box 4)
  - Rinaldi, Nicholas, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Rivard, David, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Robbins, Jhan and June, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Robbins, Tom, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Roberts, Edward B., 1955-1957 (Box 4)
  - Roberts, Kenneth, 1944-1946 (Box 4)
  - Robertson, Keith, 1963-1964 (Box 4)
  - Robertson, Mary Elsie, 1987-1988 (Box 4)
  - Robinson, Forrest A., 1978 (Box 4)
  - Robinson, Sally B., 1976 (Box 4)
  - Robison, Mary, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Rodgers, Mary Augusta, 1968-1969 (Box 4)
  - Rodman, Howard, 1960-1962 (Box 4)
  - Rodman, Selden, 1970-1971 (Box 4)
  - Root, William Pitt, undated (Box 4)
  - Ross, Nancy Wilson, 1959-1964 (Box 4)
  - Rosten, Norman, 1947-1948 (Box 4)
  - Rothenberg, Jerome, 1979-1980 (Box 4)
  - Roueche, Berton, 1962-1963 (Box 4)
  - Rovere, Richard, 1951-1952 (Box 4)
  - Rukeyser, Muriel, 1956-1977 (Box 4)
  - Russ, Joanna, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Rutsala, Vern, 1986 (Box 4)
  - R – Misc. Letters, 1941-1963 (Box 4)
  - Sadoff, Ira, 1992-1993 (Box 4)
  - Salinger, J.D., 1953-1955 (Box 4)
  - Salter, Mary Jo, 1998-1999 (Box 4)
  - Sanders, Scott, 1982-1985 (Box 4)
  - Sandoz, Mari, 1946-1948 (Box 4)
  - Santos, Sherod, 1988-1989 (Box 4)
  - Sayer, Mandy, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Sayers, Frances Clarke, 1948 (Box 4)
  - Schaffner, John, 1963-1969 (Box 4)
  - Schmitt, Gladys, 1961-1962 (Box 4)
  - Schnurr, Eileen, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Schulberg, Budd, 1950-1951 (Box 4)
  - Schwartz, Steven, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Scott, Winfield Townley, 1959 (Box 4)
  - Seager, Allen, 1961 (Box 4)
  - Seaton, Maureen, 2003-2004 (Box 4)
  - Segal, Lore, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Selby, John, 1953-1970 (Box 4)
  - Service, Pam, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Seton, Anya, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Seton, Cynthia Propper, 1981-1982 (Box 4)
  - Sexton, Anne, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Shapiro, Karl, 1945-1955 (Box 4)
  - Shaw, Harry, 1949 (Box 4)
  - Shaw, Irwin, 1941-1953 (Box 4)
  - Shaw, Robert J., 1952-1954 (Box 4)
  - Shayon, Robert Lewis, 1951 (Box 4)
  - Shepard, Sam, undated (Box 4)
  - Shepherd, Jean, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Sherburne, James, 1975 (Box 4)
  - Sherwin, Judith Johnson, 1977 (Box 4)